レベルの高いサバイバルバトルが 繰り広げられるようになる ２００階クラスからは この闘技場の最高位 ここは　戦いを望む者にとって 最高の舞台なのだ １００階クラスからは 専用の個室が与えられる 高さ９９１ｍを誇る　この建物は
I have a duty to fulfill...
俺だって半端に知るより きちんと理解したい。
They use branches that have been
ignited by lightning as live kindle.
分かりました。
Other than certain Magical
Beasts that walk on two legs, they're the first of their kind:
キルアが戦った 心源流拳法の少年　ズシ
Wow, they're really cooking it. They really are using fire!
彼が口にした 「ヨンタイギョウ」とは　何か
Hey, what else is there? Oh, yeah...
その秘密が　彼の師匠 ウイングから　今　語られる
You said the thing that attacked
me was a Chimera Ant? Yes, a Chimera Ant.
いいですか？
Under a class-1 quarantine.
ネンとは　心を燃やす「燃」のこと。
Normally, no one would be allowed
near such a dangerous insect.
すなわち　意思の強さ。
Did you discover them? No, I specialize in larger creatures.
そして　四大行とは 意思を強くする過程の修行。
But currently, I'm investigating these insects.
「意思を強くする」？ 「修行」？
Something has been bothering me...
そうです。 「点」で心を一つに集中し 自己を見つめ　目標を定める。
But it appears that now, I'll have
to move to a different location.
「舌」で　その思いを言葉にする。
I must make a call, but I'm not
getting any reception here.
「錬」で　その意思を高め
A call?
「発」で　それを行動に移す。
I'm working with others. Seven of us are working as a team.
「点」「舌」「錬」「発」。
I guess I must wait for their arrival. Once they're here, I'll introduce you.
それで四大行。 キルアくんは　ズシの「負けない」 という「錬」に気おされたのです。
They're amateurs, but they're still skilled Hunters.
では　実際に やってみせましょう　キルアくん。
Kite, who are these kids? My friends.
ん？
They dropped by for a visit on their travels.
これから　君を殺したいと思います いいですか？
Oh, it's a pleasure to meet
you all the way out here.
ああ　いいよ　無理だから。
I'm Spinner Clow. Call me Spin!
順序よく行きましょう。
Nice to meet you. I'm Gon Freecss.
まずは「点」。
Nice to meet you, Spin.
心を一つに集中。
Freecss... Wait, is this...
「舌」　これは頭で思っても 口に出しても結構です。
Yes, Ging-san's son. Really?! And you? Not you, too?
君を殺す。
My name is Killua Zoldyck. Zoldyck...
今のが「錬」です。
I handle the cooking. Know why? Because my name is Dinner.
「発」　行動に足る。
Nice meeting you.
気合で勝れば 動かずとも敵が引く。
My name is Banana Kavaro. Good to meet you.
「錬」は　ややもすると 頑固に変わり
We have two others on our team. Where are Podungo and Lin?
間違った考えを正そうとする 柔軟性を失ってしまいます。
They're both headed toward
the area of the sighting. They always move so fast.
それ故に　心が充実しないうちは 控えたほうがいい。
Oh, and you were right, Kite...
君達もズシも　今は心を鍛え 育てる時期です。
This looks just like the claw
of a Chimera Ant queen.
行こうぜ　ゴン。 もし「燃」について 学びたければ
We ran some computer analyses,
and the result was a 99% match. Can I see it?
今は「点」を極めることのみに 励みなさい。
Sure.
「点」を極めれば　相手の気概に 押されることもなくなりますよ。
This is a Chimera Ant claw? It's as big as a human finger. Does that mean there are huge ants?
ありがとうございました
Maybe one mutated and grew really big? That's possible, though it may also belong
to a completely different species.
待ってよ　キルア！
Regardless, we just don't know right now.
ズシ。 はい！
That's why we're investigating.
修行を始めるよ。 オス！
It all started with the wonkiest little thing...
まずは…。
His name was Won!
ウソ？
What's Kakin?
ああ　話も　もっともらしいし 現に　ウイングの力も 本物だと思うけど
Right here. It's this wild land, in the middle
of the Azian continent.
それだけじゃ 説明できないことがある。 え？
We had just completed a biological
survey they had requested when...
あの試合　いくら倒しても 起き上がって来るから ちょっと意地になっちゃって
Magnificent. You've completed two hundred years'
worth of work for this agency...
最後に 少し　本気　出しちゃったんだ。
To be honest, I regret that I am
unable to pay you a bonus.
)
Don't say that, Won-san.
) )
We enjoyed ourselves. In lieu of that, I'll be sure to recommend you
to other friendly nations. We appreciate it.
) )
I'm going to ramble a bit. I believe part of a very strange species was
brought to the Southern Piece auction...
((場外まで 楽々　吹き飛んだ！)) ((これは素人目にも 完璧　病院送りコース直行！)) )
There's suspicion that it's from
an unidentified organism, so the seller couldn't list it in the catalog, but since they'd have to donate it
to a government agency otherwise, they hoped a licensed Hunter would
buy it from them for a high price.
((合計１１ポイントで キルア選手のＴＫＯ勝ちです！)) )
Well, Lin? Th-This clearly belongs to an
unidentified organism, yes.
あれは　意思の強さで どうこうなるレベルを超えてるよ。
F-From what I can see,
it resembles an insect's leg...
絶対　他に秘密がある。
B-But no known insects have l-legs this large.
どうしました？　ズシ 「纏」が乱れているよ。
And the claw exhibits traits
not found among insects... A leg typically has two claws, but this has six.
師範代…。 ん？
It almost looks as though the tarsi
evolved into something like fingers?
どうして２人に ウソをついたっすか？ ウソ？　もしかして さっきの説明のことかい？
Yes, and this part is spiny,
so it could be the tibia.
そうっす！
If we take a sample and study
it further, we'll learn more.
字も意味も全然違うっす！ 門下生じゃないから ウソをついたっすか？
Could you give us a small part? Since Won-san referred you
to us, we cannot refuse.
ウソじゃ　ない。
Let's look into this, then.
「燃」は　心を鍛えるための 大切な修行だよ。
We'll send you any results, once we have them.
門下生でない者に 「念」を教えられないのも事実だ。
Chimera Ant...
それ故　方便で説くのが 燃えるほうの「燃」なんだ。
Where did Lin and Podungo go?
「念」は使い方を間違えれば
Somewhere south of Yorknew City.
恐ろしい武器になってしまうから。
The person who found the insect leg
apparently lives in a city by the ocean.
例えば…。
Sorry you won't be able to catch your breath,
but we should hurry after them.
紙切れを　やいばと化し 人を傷つけることも
Anyway, you kids are already pros at your age? We weren't born with the talent...
逆に自らの体を鋼に包み 守ることも可能。
Talent, talent... Guess I have a
talent for saying "talent," huh?
「念」は努力次第で誰にでもできる。 だからこそ　教える者は 相手を選ばねばならない。
In this brief period of time,
they've become friends. Good Hunters are well-liked by animals.
師範代　その本
And also blessed with good friends.
あっ！
Gon might be the real deal...
ジュースも　自分のっす。 ご…　ごめん！
He'll find you soon, Ging-san.
[TV]　それでは皆様　ギャンブルスイッチの 用意をお願いいたします！
Not enough... Not enough...
フッフ…。
I need more, bigger food.
なぜなら　蛇のしなやかな動きが 君の力を受け流し
It's been days...
鋭い牙が 君の急所を噛むからじゃ！
No, it's been months since it last rained here. The weather is unusual this year.
ハハハ…。 てめぇの手刀が　いくら鋭くとも 俺様の筋肉の壁は突き破れねえ！
It's possible that this is affecting
the wildlife in some way. So the insect with the large leg
なぜならば
could have been a mutation
influenced by those conditions.
厚みが違うからだ！　厚みが！
But why would it have grown larger? In order to survive, right?
ハァ…。 始め！
If it's bigger, it'd have a better
chance of securing food.
ヒュア。 テヤ！
But that would mean it'd need more, as well.
クリティカルヒット＆ダウン！
Because they reproduce in a way
not found in any other organism. What do you mean?
スリーポイント！　ノックアウト！
They reproduce through a special
process known as phagogenesis.
勝者！　ゴン！
Phagogenesis? What's that?
クリティカルヒット＆ダウン！ スリーポイント！　ノックアウト！
When a Chimera Ant queen eats other organisms, she is able to pass traits on
勝者　キルア！
from those organisms to the next generation.
またまた　一発ＫＯ勝ちです！
And she can also eat multiple species
そして２人一緒に １９０階も一発クリア！
to pass on a mix of genes to her offspring.
[TV]　２人揃って ２００階クラスへ進出です！
With each feeding, she lays one to five eggs.
もう　２００階クラスって…。 ズシ。 師範代！
The first generation of births has
no reproductive capability, so they become worker or soldier ants.
キルアくんと　ゴンくんは もう２００階ですか。 はい！　やっぱり　あの２人は すごいっす！
They work in service to the queen
and her eventual successors.
自分も　もっと…。
Those successors are the king and
queen of the next generation.
あれ？　師範代？
The queen is thus always looking to
consume the genes of strong organisms, so she can pass them to her offspring.
仕方ない…
And she may consume any species she
particularly likes to extinction.
いってらっしゃいませ。
To extinction?! Yes, her voracious appetite can drive her
どんな所かな？　２００階は。
That's why Chimera Ants are
under a class-1 quarantine.
さぁな　俺も　こっから先は 行ったことがないからなぁ。
So if she sets her eyes on you, you're finished? Judging from the size of that claw,
her length is at least two meters.
すごい！　さすがに ２００階クラスは豪華だね！
Yes, you are correct.
いよいよだね。 ああ！
B-Big Brother... Reina, stay close to me.
ただの 真っすぐな通路なのに！
Thank you! You can count on your big brother.
ダメだ…　これ以上　進めない！ 進みたくない！ これは殺気だよ！ 完全に俺達に向けられている！
That was very brave. If a big snake showed up,
your mother might be too scared to move.
クッ…。
You're truly a young man, Kurt.
おい！　一体　誰だ！ そこにいる奴！　出て来いよ！
Yeah, I guess.
キルア様と　ゴン様ですね。 こちらに受付がございますので
You must continue to look after Reina.
今日中に　２００階クラス参戦の 登録を行ってください。
I'm counting on you, Kurt. I'm counting on you, Brother.
今夜０時を過ぎますと 登録不可となりますので ご注意ください。
Yeah, you can count on me! I'll keep you both safe forever!
現在１７３名の選手が 在籍しております。
This area is about to hatch.
あ…！ あ…！
Soldiers, hear me!
え!?
In order to give birth to a strong king, I require large quantities of highly nutritious food.
あ…　ヒソカ… どうして　ここに。
This area will also hatch soon. I require a large nest in
which to birth a strong king.
僕は戦闘が好きで ここは格闘の聖地だ。
I also need time to rest, free from concerns
of outside disturbances, during the pregnancy.
君達こそ 何で　こんな所にいるんだい？ なんてね。 もちろん偶然じゃなく 君達を待っていた。
In order to give birth to a strong
king, I need strong soldiers.
電脳ネットで 飛行船のチケットを手配したろ？ あれは　ちょっとした操作で
Are you okay? Uh-huh, thank you...
誰が　どこへ　いつ行くのか 簡単に検索できるんだ。
Hey, Brother...
まぁ　いずれ　ここに来ることは 予想できたけどね。
When I grow up, I'm gonna marry you. Sure.
そこで…　ここの先輩として 君達に忠告しよう。
Let's wake up early tomorrow
and go fishing at the river. Yeah.
このフロアに 足を踏み入れるには…。
We can cook some fish to surprise Mom. Uh-huh, I can't wait.
どのくらい早いかは 君達次第。 出直したまえ とにかく　今は早い。
This is enough fish for a feast. Yep.
通さないよ。
B-Big Brother...
クッ　これは　一体…！ 何なんだ!?
Big Brother! Reina, it's okay.
無理は　やめなさい！ あ…。
I promised Mom! I'll keep you safe!
ウイングさん！
Go away!
極寒の地で　全裸で凍えながら なぜ寒いのか 分かっていないようなものです。
This is delicious, and very nutritious...
これ以上　心身に負担をかけると 死にかねないよ。
The ultimate food.
これが「燃」だと？ あいつが通さないって思うだけで こうなるっていうのか!?
I need more of this species.
はい　あれはウソです。
They're the ones I mentioned on
the phone, Gon and Killua.
正確に言うと 「ウソみたいなもの」です。
Oh, I'm Lin Koshi.
本当の「念」について教えます。
N-Nice to meet you. My name's Podungo Lapoy.
だから今は　ひとまず ここから退散しましょう。
Glad to have you on board.
ねぇ　お姉さん。 あ　はい。
Glad to be here, Lin-san, Podungo-san. Hey.
もし　今日　登録できなかったら 俺達　どうなるの？
Let's get down to business.
Where was the leg discovered? On the beach over there.
ゴン様は　また１階から 挑戦し直していただけます。 ただ　キルア様は　以前　登録を 断ってらっしゃいますから
A-According to the locals, it washed up on sh-shore.
参加自体 不可能となってしまいます。
There's a forest right behind us...
なぁ　ウイングさん。 ん？
It'll be difficult to find the
Chimera Ant if it ran in there.
ひとまず引いて ０時までに戻って来られるか？
We can't be certain that it's still alive.
ここに…。
We don't even know if it ended up
on the same island its leg drifted to.
それは　君達次第だ。
Here, remember this scent.
分かりやすく例えると これが「念」です。
His nose is as sharp as a dog's.
その生命エネルギーを 肉体にとどめる技術を
He can't find anything... The scent may have disappeared.
「纏」と言います。
It was raining.
これによって　肉体は頑強となり
I couldn't find anything, either.
常人より はるかに若さを保てます。
That means the Chimera Ant isn't here.
そして「絶」 字のごとく　オーラを絶つ技術。
It may have washed ashore elsewhere. In which direction do the currents flow here?
気配を消したり 極度の疲労を癒やす時などに
It's complicated...
効果があります。
The direction is reversed
between day and night.
そして「練」。
And it also changes with the seasons.
通常以上のオーラを生み出す技術。
I've even heard it's different on certain days. So it'll be tough to pinpoint a location...
感じますか？ ああ…　圧迫感がある。
Let's split up and search. You're right.
恐らく　生まれ育った環境も あるだろう
No luck... Continuing to search blindly is pointless.
…が　本人の資質によるところが 大きい
Let's return to Yorknew City.
オーラは　人間の 内部から発するエネルギー。
We may be able to find a new lead.
オーラだけで人を殺せます。
Her length is at least two meters.
「念」の使い手から 身を守る方法は一つだけ。
That thing could devour a human in no time.
自分も「念」の使い手になること。
A voracious appetite...
「纏」による防御のみ！
Phagogenesis.
あ…。 あ…。
So that I may fully receive, understand, and execute your orders.
肉体は粉々に壊されてしまいます。
That pleases me. I assign you to be a squadron leader.
２００階クラスの前に 立ちはだかったヒソカ
I already have your mission. Lead all the soldiers here on a mission
果たして　ゴンは　キルアは
to capture my food...
本当の「念」を習得して 受け付けが終了する ０時までの間に
Capture more of those highly
nutritious organisms for me.
ヒソカの壁を 突破することができるのか！
At once!
まだ…　早い！
A Chimera Ant has been born with human genes.